Alright, listen up, everybody!
Today,
we're talkin' about the You-Nix Vee Six File System,
alright?
Now,
don't you go gettin' all scared with those fancy words.
It's just a way to organize stuff on your computer,
like how I organize my fridge – chaos,
but organized chaos!
So, you got your directories, right?
Think of 'em like folders.
And inside those folders, you got your files.
Now,
in You-Nix Vee Six,
you gotta understand the tree structure.
You got your root directory,
that's like the big papa folder,
represented by a slash.
Now, inside that root directory,
you got other directories like bin,
etc,
and dev.
Bin is where all the executable files live –
that's just a fancy word for files that do stuff.
Etc is where the system config files hang out.
And dev?
Well, that's where all the device files are.
Don't go messin' around in there unless you know what you're doin',
alright?
You don't want to be like Brian,
poking around where he shouldn't be.
And inodes?
Those are like the ID cards for each file and directory.
They keep track of all the important info.
So,
that's the You-Nix Vee Six File System in a nutshell.